Koraima Sotomayor Enríquez

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

PROACTIVE, CURIOUS, HARD-WORKING, AND KIND [SHE/HER]

I have worked as an accredited psychologist in Ecuador with children and adults using EBPs.I contributed in research projects during my undergraduate studies, and later on I continued being involved in research as an independent researcher. Currently, I am collaborating with the implementation of Phase 1 from the IMMERSE project and I am part of the Butterfly Baby Clinic team an honorary Research Assistant.

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH | PhD Clinical Psychology (Ongoing)

Sep 2021 - August 2024 (expected) | Edinburgh, Scotland

Academic Scholarships: Partial Scholarship as part of a Studentship with the IMMERSE project

THE UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH | MSc Psychological Research (Merit)

Sep 2020 - Sep 2021 | Edinburgh, Scotland

NEUROCORP - UNIVERSIDAD INTERNACIONAL DEL ECUADOR

DIPLOMA IN EXPERTISE IN EVIDENCE BASED PSYCHOTHERAPY

November 2019 - May 2020 | Quito, Ecuador

UNIVERSIDAD INTERNACIONAL DEL ECUADOR | BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY WITH

HONOURS (SUMA CUM LAUDE)

Sep 2011 – Jan 2017 | Quito, Ecuador Final Grade: 97.54/100

Academic Scholarships: March – July 2012 / September 2012 – January 2013 / March – July 2013 / September 2013 – January 2014 / March – July 2014 / September 2014 – February 2015 / April – August 2015 / September 2015 – January

2016 / April - August 2016

Awards: Best graduate at ceremony of graduation

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Moderate: • LATEX • R

 $\textbf{Familiar/Studying}: \bullet \textbf{Python} \bullet \textbf{bash-shell}$

SOFTWARE

Moderate: •SPSS •Office •Google Drive •Qualtrics

Familiar/Studying: •jamovi •MATLAB

Graphic Design: •Adobe Illustrator •Adobe Premiere

LANGUAGES

French	(A1) The University of Edinburgh - short courses	Ongoing
	IELTS overall score: 7.5	13 February 2020
English	TOEFL® iBT total score: 102	5 January 2019
	(C1) Proficiency Certificate by CEC-EPN	27 October 2012
Ecuadorian Sign Language	(A1) Deaf People Association of Pichincha	25 January 2018
Spanish	(L1) Native fluency	

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

- Impact of siblings in Theory of Mind Behavioural and Neurofunctional Responses Master Dissertation Project OSF Pre-Registration: osf.io/hyvxn
- An integer programming model to assign patients based on mental health impact for tele-psychotherapy intervention during the Covid-19 emergency
 Health Care Management Science, 23, 2020
 https://doi.org/10.1007/s10729-020-09543-z
- Dissertation title: "Actitudes de rechazo hacia gays y lesbianas: validación y comparación de dos instrumentos que miden homofobia" [Attitudes of rejection against gays and lesbians: a validation and comparison of two tools to measure homophobia] •https://repositorio.uide.edu.ec/handle/37000/1779

EXPERIENCE

TUTOR RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Edinburgh - Scotland

February 2022 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Tutor, organise and facilitate weekly tutorials during academic period to contribute towards a creative learning environment.
- Facilitate discussion and foster critical analysis of the content of the course during tutorials.
- Mark assignments following standards and regulations of the course organiser.
- Liaise with course organiser, other tutors, and students to carry out marking responsibilities and other relevant activities.

1001 THINK TANK PROJECT RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Edinburgh - Scotland

February 2022 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Support the organisation of this collaboration via calendar invites, meeting attendance and associated minutes
- Design and deliver digital resources in collaboration with the team.
- Organise sub-teams and liaise with students involved in the project.
- Participate in activities related with the project in collaboration with stackholders and students.

NEURODESARROLLO QUITO PSYCHOLOGIST

Hospital Metropolitano - Torres Médicas II, Consultorio 414. San Gabriel y Nicolas Arteta – Quito

Aug 2019 – Sep 2020

Responsibilities:

- Assess clients with neuropsychological test, interviews, and clinical observation.
- Implement psychological interventions with children with learning disabilities and behaviour problems.
- Coaching parents in behaviour management skills.
- Conduct evidence psychotherapy process with adults (PTSD, Mood Disorders).
- Write and edit psychological reports from psychological assessments.
- Manage and organise local and international events such as "I Congreso Panamericano de Autismo, Síndrome X Frágil y Trastornos del Neurodesarrollo" [I Panamerican Congress on Autism, Fragile X Syndrome and Neurodevelopmental Disorders].

VOLUNTEERING

CAPS - ETHIC MINORITIES GROUP VOLUNTEER

Online Volunteering - Edinburgh January 2022 – Ongoing

BUTTERFLY BABY CLINIC HONORARY RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Online Volunteering - Edinburgh May 2021 – Ongoing

FUNDACIÓN DE DIABETES JUEVENIL DEL ECUADOR [ECUADORIAN FOUNDATION OF JUVENILE

DIABETES] - ASSOCIATE PSYCHOLOGIST

Isla Santa Fe N43-65, Quito - Ecuador

Enero 2018 - Septiembre 2020

AFFILIATIONS

Graduate Member of the British Psychological Society (BPS) [2021,2022]

PhD Student of the Centre for Applied Developmental Psychology (CADP) at the University of Edinburgh [2021, 2022]

INTERESTS

Creative writing • Open Science and Reproducibility • Singing • Walks • Drawing • 🗪 Behaviour Sciences • 🜢 Journaling